What if I told you
that you could make more money in a single
day than the
entire year before it?
But this method isn't just slept on, it's
underrated. And that method
is doing events.
Now, just before I get into the nuts
and bolts of it, I'm James Smith.
I'm originally a personal trainer,
and I ran my first fat loss seminar all
the
way back in 2017. But five years later,
I sold out the Hammersmith Apollo and
then the Sydney Opera House.
And I put a link in the description to
this for my
upcoming events in Sydney and Dubai.
So please click on those
if you want to get tickets and attend.
I started my life doing events for the
very reason you're probably thinking.
To grow the brand, to get myself-- No,
for free flights.
My parents live back in the United
Kingdom. So back in 2017, I
was a bit skint.
I was thinking,
"How could I get a trip home to see my
family and get the
business to pay for it?" I'm going to do
an event in Bracknell, which is where the
budgie gym I used to work at was.
I remember driving past a hotel quite
frequently to go to rugby training.
I called them up.
"Can I book an event space?" Then I'm
pretty sure I went onto Eventbrite for the
ticketing. And with 12,000 followers,
I went on sale.
And the way I saw it was even
if the event didn't make any money,
that was fine.
If I got my flight for free, it
was about £550 to fly with Etihad
in economy. I was laughing. Now, this
is not financial advice,
but for any of you
listening, anything that you can say
is exclusively and wholly for the
business,
it's not free,
but you can get your business to pay for
it.
So if you wanted to buy a MacBook Pro,
just for work, if you bought it in your
personal name,
it might cost you up to £1,500,
but then you'd have to earn over
£2,000, pay the tax on it,
then have the money to buy the MacBook.
But if your business pays for it,
that doesn't happen.
Because what it does
is it reduces your profitability.
Businesses have to pay tax.
It's called corporation tax. But
when your business spends money on
essentials,
such as a MacBook Pro,
the government look at the amount of
profit that you made
for the year, and it's reduced,
because some money went towards purchasing
things.
I wish that my mate Darren understood
that when I bought him business class
flights. He was like, "Yeah, calm, bruv.
Business expense." I'm like,
"That doesn't mean it's free."
But the beautiful thing
about any of you that
are in the world of content creation
is that technically,
again, not financial advice, if you
were going to go to Ibiza
and create lots of
content, do a bit of networking,
go to some meetings,
maybe scope out some event
spaces for a seminar
that you're running next year,
you could turn around and say,
"Look, I didn't even want to go.
I had to go exclusively and wholly for the
business to look at venues." So your first
event doesn't even have to make money.
That's the beautiful thing about this.
If I'm completely honest with you,
my first two tours
that I ever did lost money.
But we always repeated the same mantra.
If we give people a really good
experience, next year they'll come back,
but with
friends.
And the second thing I need to be honest
about, this Stripe payment here
of what? $56,000?
That wasn't just from the event, I'll be
honest.
That actually had nothing to do with the
event.
That's just from the sales I made from
that day.
All the ticket money for
that event didn't even go into
that Stripe account.
For any of you that have ever come to my
business events before, I used to run them
for personal trainers. Because before,
I had a $20 million drinks brand, and a
business mentorship,
and an investment into the UK's biggest
TRT company.
Before all those things, it
was just coaches.
And I'd open my PT events, I'd say, "Hey,
guys, do you want to hear a joke?
Working on weekends." No one would laugh,
because so many personal trainers in that
room actually had to work weekends,
which I still think is crazy.
I was like, "Hey, guys,
you want to hear another joke?
Working after 5:00 PM."
And most personal trainers were like,
"That's our bread and
butter. Time to do PT." I was like,
"That's the biggest lie you've ever been
fed."
Because the gym is the most busiest after
5:00 PM, and the experience that you give
someone in that time is the worst. "I
was just going to queue for a leg press
while
you pay me £40 an hour." Anyway,
if you are a PT working evenings
and weekends,
there's a bundle
that I put in the description below,
so you can stop doing that.
Back to the events.
We first need to distinguish B2B versus
B2C. B2B means business to business.
So for my events in Sydney and Dubai,
that is me working with other businesses.
I can charge more money for
that because people coming can just
download that
invoice, give it to their accountant,
and it's a tax deductible.
Again, exclusively
and wholly for the business.
So even if I was charging £2,000 for the
day, their business can pay for it.
They don't have to earn the income,
pay tax on it, et cetera.
When we look at B2C, business to customer,
you're probably going to go higher
volume, lower ticket point. People
are paying for that with their post-tax
income,
and it's going to be slightly different
things you're going to do.
So let's first look at B2C events. So
that started off with my Fat Loss Seminar
in
Bracknell. Sold 187 tickets.
I'm going to overlay some footage of
that event now. As you can see,
I look back at myself and think, "Wow."
First of all, quite impressive.
Second of all, what are you wearing?
Third of all,
why have I got such a podgy face?
And yeah, even the fact I
was organized enough to have a
videographer there.
Flipping mental. Then after that, in 2019,
got my first book deal.
So we started doing book tours,
where we do signings at the event.
So I get to the event at 3:00 PM,
sign everyone's books, do the live event,
and
then we go out and get pissed with them
afterwards.
We actually threw several after-parties,
and the after-parties were so much fun, we
actually thought, "Okay,
let's do another in-person B2C event."
And I
worked with my events team to create
something called IFS,
International Fitness
Summit. Now, it's been offline for a year,
but it's coming back next year, bigger,
better, and in HD. And IFS was crazy.
It's where we got all some of the best
people in the fitness industry,
brought them
together to Barcelona in our first year.
Then we did Lisbon, then we did London.
Bloody good times. Now,
just before we get into the
business-to-business thing, I
actually have a confession to make.
So much of what I teach you now,
I actually learned from my first business
talk.
In 2015,
it would've been in the DoubleTree Hilton
in Victoria.
Now,
this is going to sound really petty
and pathetic, but there's kind of an
OG in the fitness industry
that I learnt so much from, and I'm so
grateful to everything that he taught me,
to the point that he quite literally
was like my dad of the fitness industry.
And I used to go to him whenever I had any
issues.
I used to go to him whenever I had any
troubles.
I actually used to go to him whenever I
had any wins.
I studied under him,
and I would probably admit that I
was one of his golden boys.
Out of all of us that
were doing his course, I was the one
that just seemed to be
making leaps and bounds,
and every time I could,
I'd drop him a message and be
like, "Mate,
your course has changed my life." Anyway,
without going into too much
detail or getting into a legal court case
about it or whatever, I once went to him
for help and it backfired on me.
And to be perfectly honest, it
was completely my
fault. I'd made the mistake. But at
that time that I went to him for help,
even
though it was my fault,
he kind of screwed me over.
And I was in a time in my life where I had
just broken up with my girlfriend who I
was living with and whose visa I was on.
I had to leave Australia in 2018.
I didn't know if I was coming back.
And I borderline begged him, and he still
pressed me. And for that reason,
I'll never mention his name in any of the
videos.
And even though I learnt so much from him,
went to his days, I used to get sweaty
armpits at the end just shaking his hand
because he was my idol.
And now we don't talk, and it's a shame.
Because the amount of business
that I would've sent him since 2018
would've been
crazy.
I've actually got his name in the notes.
I thought I'd get to a point of
forgiveness and actually just big him up
and give
him the credit, but no.
I learnt so much on
that day with the guy that's not to be
named. It's like Voldemort.
We could just call him Voldemort from here
on in.
Literally changed my life.
And at the event,
it wasn't just the slides, the
presentations, the things we
were going through.
It was that I was actually in front of
him. I was nervous around him.
I was like, "Oh my God, it's like an aura.
It's like an energy." But it was
that he is just a normal human being.
And then during lunch,
you could just chat to him and be like,
"Wow." A normal guy.
So there's the energy of actually just
being with people that you respect in the
industry and actually being like, "Oh,
what are you up to this weekend?" The
second
was looking around at all the other people
at the event. I was like, oh.
In my head,
everyone in the fitness industry
was super jacked, super buff, in
amazing shape. I looked around, I'm like,
these are just normal people.
In my head, the fitness industry
was full of demigods, but
when you get there,
you're like, "Oh, actually,
all of my peers are exactly the same as
me." None of us
are in competing bodybuilding shape.
We're all here on a Saturday morning
trying to better ourselves.
So the energy I was getting from not only
the person taking the event, but from the
other people in the room was amazing.
It was motivating. I
was getting gassed up.
The only person in that room that
was in crazy shape was Jamie Auderton,
and that
was the first time I met him, so
that would've been 2015.
Then I think about other people,
hugely influential.
For instance, even Paul Moore.
Some of you might know,
some of you might not.
Guy from South Shields in the UK.
I learned a lot about my email marketing
from
Paul. I hired him as a coach.
He's opened some of my live events.
So how cool is that? Someone
that I studied under, a few years later,
I got him to
open my live events
and speak at my events because of the
value that I think he
brings to it. And even the guarantee.
So for instance, the Sydney
and Dubai event, I've said that
if you come to the
event, you don't love it by lunchtime,
it's not everything you thought and more,
let me know. You can leave the event.
I'll refund your ticket, your flights,
and your hotel.
That is Paul's guarantee
that got me to go to one of his events.
So anyway, it all comes together.
And even if I look back to some of the fat
loss
seminars that I went on, which
was still business to business because I
was
learning about how to help my clients lose
fat, there are still things from the
slideshow that I saw on that day
that I still regurgitate now.
One of the slides went,
"Fat loss isn't donut to broccoli,
fat loss is
donut to half a donut,
or donut to low-calorie ice cream."
And that stuck with me
so well in person at the event
that I can still regurgitate it, what,
nearly 11
years later. Wow.
So let's get into perfecting the perfect
business-to-business
talk and get through some of the key
principles that you might want to
understand
before doing one yourself. First of all,
we have the duration of the talk.
The golden rule is you're better off
leaving people wanting more than giving
them
too much. But actually at these events,
even though the talk shouldn't drag
on too much,
you're probably going to be there the
whole day.
So in my mind,
the talk's probably going to go from 10:00
to 3:00.
We're going to get an hour for lunch,
and in that time, I'm going to jam pack as
much information as I can.
What we're going to talk about,
get onto that in a
second. Then 3:00, 4:00, maybe 5:00,
depending on the event, the location,
whatever,
I'm going to give people the opportunity
to leave.
Because some people have come from far
away and they need to get a flight, they
need to get a train,
they need to get back to where they are.
But then the rest of the time,
signing books, getting selfies,
talking to people.
I usually don't leave the event
or the venue till about 7:00 PM.
So I will arrive 8:00 AM,
maybe 7:00 AM to do laptop
check, make sure
that the presentation works and
that everything's all right.
There's a charger.
I might be in the event space for 12
hours.
By the end of it, my social battery
is so cooked that when I get home
and see my
parents, I just don't talk to them.
My dad's like, "How was your day,
son?" Good.
That's it. Now, the talk, usually,
I create from scratch based on
the last three months in my Discord.
So whatever people
are talking about in the Discord,
whether it's landing pages,
conversions, new software, new trends,
whatever it is,
they're going to be the main
components of it.
I like to treat each business day as
if most people came to the
last one. So it's not just one talk
that you keep doing and doing and doing.
I will sit in front of a blank canvas,
and I will think about what are the things
that I've been talking about recently,
what are the problems that I've been
solving, how could I best address
that to people?
Because there's that kind of pop culture
element of people worrying about the same
things. If we can tap into that,
we can really, really hit some nerves.
But it was B2C with the book events.
I'd spent a year writing a book,
it's like 360 pages.
I was like, okay, what
are the 10 best lessons inside this book?
I would then make them into something in
the show where I could say, right, here's
the lesson, here's an analogy.
What kind of joke can I put in there?
So it's a bit of a pacing where it's like
TED Talk, fingering jokes, TED Talk,
fingering jokes. Anyone of you
that have been to a live event,
you might have known
that. Any of you that haven't, fine.
Then another question, you're like, okay,
so how do you make this different from
what's in the course already? Well,
the issue is you actually don't.
You take what is working for people
and helping them, you bring it to life.
And the idea of the talk to me
is actually to get questions out of
people.
So I'm not just there like clicking
through slides.
I'm going to talk about something.
I'm going to have my opinion.
Then I'm going to ask people about theirs.
The whole point of a good talk to me,
especially B2B, is what can I talk
about for five minutes to get questions
out of the audience?
Then when the questions come out to me,
I just answer them on the spot.
And again,
I can always just say to people,
"I don't know," but rarely does that
happen. And I just make sure
that I segment enough time so we can talk
about
content, sales process, email marketing,
whatever it is.
And a lot of the time, if those
are into four quarters,
a bit like every good book
should have four different stages in it.
Someone says, "Oh,
ask a question about..." Can we wait until
the very end?
Because that's going to be the fourth
thing we talk about today.
We'd go into different cohorts about
different parts of the business strategy,
whatever it is, do it that way.
With the B2C events,
I would often go through the
chronological order of the book because
if an editor and I worked together for a
year to make sure the information should
be in a certain way, the show should be
the end. Because if an editor and I
are going to work for a year to make sure
that
everything's in the right order,
in the show,
it probably makes sense to have it in
the same.
Then it's always good to have something to
finish the show
with to get people to leave
and think about.
Now, with the frequency of these events,
you can start to spot patterns and trends
of the feedback you're getting from the
audience about what problems they're
solving,
and then you can amend the talk for the
following week or month or year,
whenever you do it. So
if we now take a step back
and we go into point two, how can
we use in-person events to grow our actual
physical business?
First of all, we're going to run signups.
Out of those signups,
we're going to get a lot of data.
Out of that data,
we're going to be able to sell tickets.
Now,
with the money you're going to get from
the tickets, first of all, you should
have enough for the venue to pay the
venue,
and you might have some to cover your
ad spend,
so you might have done some paid ads
running signups.
Not to mention, at this stage,
you probably should have an email list
and some warm
leads that you can go out to just through
email marketing to get people on board.
For me, very much at the moment,
I actually take venue cost, hire,
AV, whatever it is, ad spend,
running signups.
I get that number,
and then I divide it by the amount of
seats at the venue so that
if I sell out the venue,
I'm at a break even.
For me,
it's not so much about needing to make
money from the event because I know
that maybe 50%, maybe 60%,
70% of the people at the event just want
to come for the
day. They don't want to be sold anything.
I want my margins to come from people
that buy into my program, not people
that buy
to sit on a seat. The second thing
that a lot of people overlook
is the impact of
getting content at that event.
What I'll do now is I'll show you some
content from
the first business event I ever did in
2019.
Now, what was interesting here,
for this venue,
we got the venue for 24 hours.
So I decided, okay,
let's do a B2B event throughout the whole
day.
So I did 10:00 till 5:00 at the B2B event.
Went back to my hotel in Shoreditch.
Pretty sure I had a shower, a wank,
a little nap, and then came back for the
evening event that went from like 7:00 to
10:00. So the venue cost stayed the same.
We ran a B2B and a B2C event.
Fucking exhausted at the end of it.
So then you've got content from previous
events, like we used in the onset of this
video, to sell future events.
And the more content you have,
the more clips you
have.
You might even have a clip from the event
that bags you a client online six
months down the line. And often,
even though I've earned heinous amounts of
money
to do these events, even
that event where I did, what,
$56,000 in a day, truth
be told, at the end of it,
when I looked at all the content we'd got
for paid ads
and everything else,
I would've done it for free.
Don't tell my manager that,
because he'll be like, "Oh."
[rubbing palms] Now,
one of the best things that you can do,
not just at the end,
but during, is have a Q&A section,
especially for B2B.
If you're B2C,
sometimes we would do a Q&A at the end.
One thing I would say is
if you're in an audience of maybe several
hundred
people,
you can just throw a QR code up on the
screen, get people to ask questions
during an intermission,
then you can pick the best ones to answer.
This also just stops you from someone
spending two minutes asking a question
that
you don't know the answer to. So why
is it that I'm here proclaiming you should
do
that,
but so many other people don't do these
events? Well, one, fear.
People are just worried they're going to
do an event and 10 people are going to
show up. Fine. Social battery.
Some people are just not prepared to spend
12 hours
with people. And three,
some people would rather do just the
mastermind in Bali or
Dubai. And again,
I'll tell you why I don't do this.
Let's say I want to make 100 grand for a
day.
What I do not want to do
is have 10 people that pay 10 grand.
And although I've been told to do this
loads, that stresses me out.
If you're paying me 10 grand for a
weekend, I feel like you own me.
And if you're like, "James,
can I have a minute?" "Yes. Anything else?
Do you want a massage?" I just don't want
that stress.
I'd rather have a room full of people
that spend $600 and I'm like, "Look,
you're
going to get your money's worth no matter
what, or you get your money back." But 10
grand each, just not my bag.
But another way these in-person events can
grow your
brand and your business is a lot of,
quote-unquote, "influencers" think their
audiences are dumb or stupid
or inferior or whatever.
Our audiences are incredibly smart
and they pick up on the smallest of cues.
They're going to watch you for hours,
and they're going to see who the real
version
of you is,
because you can't hold a facade for
that long.
The way you banter,
you interact with someone,
your level of empathy, your
manners, everything. And it's at
that moment in the book signing where you
can show
off your idiosyncrasies, the things
that are unique that make you you.
It's only at that moment
that people can make a snapshot judge
about who you
are.
And if you are the person they want you to
be, and you're genuine, you're
polite,
you've got someone who's going to buy into
your brand for life.
Eight years down the line,
they're going to go, "Yeah, I met her.
She's amazing.
She's so kind. You should do her app.
Oh my God, you should buy her book.
You should buy her jump rope. Oh,
it's the best thing ever." There's even
the
little times where you're at the place of
the event, say you're in Newcastle,
Leeds, Sydney, or whatever.
People know you're in the area, so
when they see you in
the street, they're like, "Oh, James.
I'm coming to your event tonight."
And rather than just being like,
"Cheers." "Oh,
where have you come from? Oh,
that's amazing.
I won't hold it against you.
Birmingham.
Ugh." You have this huge opportunity all
the way around the
event to really get people to buy into
what you're doing.
And if you're naturally like that, great.
So what should you do with the information
that you're learning in this video?
Well, first of all,
you should start to think about the first
event you could do.
Now that I've told you it doesn't even
have to run at a profit, that should
alleviate quite a bit of the stress.
I would obviously say come to one of my
events so you can just copy me and see how
I do it. But ultimately,
for some of you that might be in your
infancy, this is
where I'm going to be pretty much pitching
in my mentorship.
There's going to be a link about working
with me in the description.
Because in there, to sell an event,
you can't just put an event out.
You need people to buy into you
and your brand.
And to do that,
you need to accrue a lot of goodwill.
The only way you can accrue a lot of
goodwill is by helping people.
So if you're someone who's got 10,000
followers or more and 2,000 people on your
email list,
you can start looking at event spaces
and get going.
But for those of you under 10,000
followers,
you just haven't done enough of the
very things that I teach.
And very briefly, content.
It means putting out content on several
platforms, helping people, solving their
problems. And engagement
is a good metric of how good
that content is.
I've never seen people create amazing
content for long periods of time and never
take off.
[exhales] We need some component of email
marketing.
Again, not just for your business
and your brand, but so that
when you launch an
event, you can say, "Hey, guys.
I'm going to be in London on this event.
Do you want to come?" Ticket sales. Ding,
ding, ding, ding, ding.
You're going to need landing pages
that highly convert so you can send people
to
them, so they can buy your product
and your offer.
Again,
because you're going to have to do
that with tickets the same way you do
with your service or your product.
And here's the lesson from events you can
apply to your whole business.
Your first event will not make $56,000 in
a day.
But if people want to know why I like to
think my events are good or that I don't
get nervous before them,
it's because I've done loads of them.
I've been on four tours B2C,
done maybe a dozen business events in
person.
No one watched my content for years.
Now they watch it.
No one bought my stuff for years.
Now they buy it.
If you can treat events just like any
other component of your business,
like email
marketing, like content,
like growing an audience,
you just compound.
Then one day you could do an event
that when you
leave, you email everyone
that came with an offer
and you get enough money to buy a
Lamborghini or something less
materialistic.
So you've got your PT bundle in the
description.
I've given you the Work With Me link.
And the third one that's going to be
there,
it's going to be called 30 Ways in 30
Days. The truth is,
I've not built out the lead magnet to
capture your data for
events. But if you
are interested in coming to one of my
future events that's not
in Sydney or Dubai,
you'll have to sign up on that one.
And I hope that not all of you
are personal trainers,
because I'm trying to move
away from that niche. But if you
are a personal trainer,
watch this video here,
because it will help you maybe even more
than this one.